nrma.com.au 2015-12-05

# Privacy, Security & Identity Theft | NRMA Insurance

When we collect your personal information, our commitment to the protection and privacy of your personal information is a priority.

Our **Privacy Policy** provides details about the management of your personal information including:

Our **Online Privacy Statement** and our **Online Security Statement** provide further details concerning the management of your personal information online.

In these documents, the terms “we”, “our” and “us” refer to Insurance Australia Limited ABN 11 000 016 722 (trading as NRMA Insurance) and its related entity Insurance Manufacturers of Australia Pty Limited ABN 93 004 208 084.

If you have any questions about privacy and security, please email us or call us on [**132 132**](tel:132132) 7am-10pm, 7 days.

## _ _ Read the Online Security Statement for this website

Please read this statement along with our Privacy Policy.

We take the protection of your personal information very seriously, so we regularly revise and update our security measures to keep your information private and meet industry standards.  

### Steps we take to protect your information

  * We encrypt your information as it travels between your computer and our computers. We use a form of Transport Layer Security (TLS) to stop anyone intercepting your information.
  * Your personal information is stored on computer systems which are protected by a combination of firewalls, secure logon processes, encryption and intrusion monitoring technologies.
  * We use a recognised payment service provider to process any insurance payments you make using this website. This service provider is committed to protecting your personal information on our behalf.
  * In certain circumstances we will collect and use your IP address to protect the security of our website.
  * We regularly test our websites and infrastructure for vulnerabilities and take action where needed.
  * We apply security patches to software provided by vendors.

### Steps you can take to protect your information

It’s still very important that you take some steps to help keep up security when you’re online:

  * Protect your personal information, such as usernames, passwords and policy details, by not allowing anyone to see you entering them, and avoid public wi-fi usage.
  * Notify us as soon as possible if you become aware of any security breaches.
  * Use a strong password for your account. Try to think of something that is easy to remember, but hard to guess, such as a passphrase.
  * Change your password regularly and try not to reuse the same password on more than one site.
  * Don’t let your browser save your password for our websites.
  * Be wary of websites, emails or phone calls that claim to be from us. Please contact us if you are unsure.
  * Keep an eye on your accounts and check for any unauthorised transactions.
  * Keep your devices up to date with firewall enabled, anti-malware software, anti-virus software and security updates.

### How do you make sure you’re going to the right website?

Always go directly to our website by typing the address **www.nrma.com.au** rather than following links found in emails or elsewhere online.

### Keeping safe with email

  * Never disclose personal, financial or debit/credit card information by email. Contact us if you’re unsure of the legitimacy of any email that appears to have come from us.
  * We will never ask for sensitive or personal information such as usernames, passwords or policy details if you haven’t asked for our help first.

By helping us with these things, we can both work to make your world a safer place. To report any concerns around the security or privacy of your information please email [cybersecurity@iag.com.au](mailto:cybersecurity@iag.com.au).

Read more at [StaySmartOnline, an Australian Government online safety and security website](https://www.communications.gov.au/what-we-do/internet/stay-smart-online).

## _ _ Read the Online Privacy Statement

This Online Privacy Statement applies to this website, located at www.nrma.com.au, which is operated and managed by us for us and our related entities. This Online Privacy Statement supplements and should be read in conjunction with our Privacy Policy.

### Our commitment to privacy and responsible use of your online personal information

When you use this website and when you transact with us online, we are committed to protecting the privacy of your personal information, and to handling your personal information in a responsible manner in accordance with the Privacy Act.

### What information do we collect when you interact with us online?

The information that we collect from you when you interact with us online depends on the tasks you complete on this website.

### Browsing this website

When you visit and browse this website, we collect general information that enables us to continually evaluate and improve the performance of this website. This general information includes:

  * The number of users visiting this website and the number of pages viewed
  * The date, time and duration of visits
  * The path taken through this website

### Applying for a product or service or making a payment

We need to obtain personal information from you in order to complete your online application for our products or services, or to identify you if you are paying for your products or services online.

When paying for a product or service online, we require your policy number, email address, suburb and payment details. We use a recognised payment service provider to process any insurance payments you make using this website. This service provider is committed to protecting your personal information on our behalf.

### Enquiries, Emails and Email Forms

To send an email to us, or to make an enquiry online, you will need to complete an email form available on this website. Many of our online forms ask for a limited amount of personal information for contact purposes, such as an email address or telephone number. You have the choice of whether or not to provide additional personal information.

Information provided to us either directly or indirectly through these forms will be used for the purposes outlined above, such as to answer your enquiry or to provide the estimate requested.

### Online Surveys

When you visit this website you may be invited to participate in an online survey, which will appear as a pop-up window. Participation in any survey is voluntary, and we will generally not ask you for your name. This survey may ask you to provide information such as your age, gender and income.

### How information is collected

Information that is not capable of identifying you, such as the number of users visiting this website, is collected through code embedded in the webpages of this website. You cannot disable the code on these pages.

Other information, such as browser type, is included in a ‘cookie’ that is sent to your computer when you are completing certain tasks on this website. A cookie contains bits of information that enables our servers (ie. the computers that house this website) to identify and interact efficiently with your computer. Cookies are designed to provide a better, more customised website experience, and to make it easier for you to use this website.

You can configure your browser to either accept all cookies, reject all cookies or to notify you when a cookie is being sent to your computer. The ‘help function’ on your browser will provide you with details on how to change your browser configurations. You will need to accept cookies in order to use some functionality on this website.

We may also use technologies similar to cookies in emails you receive either directly from us or from third party email providers sending emails on our behalf. These technologies help us understand whether you have opened the email, and how you have interacted with it. They also help us understand what you may find of interest and can assist us, for example, in tailoring the advertising we display to you on websites where we have an arrangement in place to serve advertisements. If you prefer not to be tracked in this way you can disable HTML images or refuse HTML (select Text only) within your email software, and you should not click on any links within the email (with the exception of the unsubscribe link). You can opt-out from receiving these emails at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link within the email.

### How we use information collected online - Selling or distribution of information

We do not sell, trade, lease or rent any personally identifiable information we obtain using this website, without your prior consent.

### Third Party Suppliers

From time to time we may use independent third party suppliers to gather information using code embedded in the webpages of this website. This information includes information such as the number of users and pages viewed and the path taken through this website. We use this information for statistical and maintenance purposes. We may also use independent third party suppliers to collect information from emails you receive from us or our email providers. This information includes information such as how the email has been interacted with, and visits to other websites. We also use other external companies and may disclose your personal and non-personal information to them for the following purposes:

**For web hosting services for this website**

**For maintenance or problem-solving**

**To gather information from cookies in order to evaluate the effectiveness of our online activities**

### What is our privacy relationship with third party websites?

This website includes hyperlinks to enable you to access a number of other websites by clicking on these hyperlinks we have provided. These third party websites are not subject to this Online Privacy Statement. We recommend that you read their privacy and security statements to understand how they deal with your personal information online.

### This Online Privacy Statement operates from 15th May 2014

Due to evolving technologies and types of functionality available on this website, we encourage you to review this Online Privacy Statement from time to time as it may be updated. Your continued use of this website or the provision of further personal information to us after this Online Privacy Statement has been revised constitutes your acceptance of the revised Online Privacy Statement.

Identity Theft is where a criminal is able, through deception, to obtain enough personal and information about you so as to fool organisations into believing they are dealing with their customer. This is a significant problem in Australia today and it's important to keep an eye on any policies you hold.

One common signal that you are the target of identity crime is unexpected changes to your bank and insurance policies. 

If you think that there's been changes to your insurance policies with us that you suspect were caused by an unauthorised person, such as the addition of new policies, or changes to your address or date of birth, please contact us on **[132 132](tel:132132)**
